DEE XIAO「萧笛」

+86 (186) 0164-0024 mopjtv@hotmail.com deexiao.com

个人简介

本科、研究生毕业于美国亚利桑那州立大学,能够为产品应用带来多样化的技术和创造性的驱动影响力。熟练使用多种语言编写代码,并能进行特性开发与实现。专业独立思想,为困难的工程问题找到独特的解决方案。

教育经历

「美国 本科 」 理学学士, 计算机科学 <u>亚利桑那州立大学 - 美国</u> *GPA*: 3.6 / 4.0 2012 年 08 月 - 2017 年 05 月 「美国 硕士 」 理学硕士, 计算机科学 亚利桑那州立大学 - 美国 *GPA*: 3.4 / 4.0 2018 年 01 月 - 2019 年 01 月

专业技能

• 移动端开发 (iOS & Android): Obj-C / Swift, Java/Kotlin

• PC端开发: React, Vue, Webpack, TS, MapTalks, ECharts ...

• 后端开发语言: C++, ASP.NET

• 版本控制系统: 多年 Git 版本管理经验 和 NPM 等包管理经验

• 产品技能: Axure, Viso, MindManager, Figma

工作经验

「前端开发」 脉策数据科技(上海)

2021年11月-至今

• 根据数据模型算法和地理信息,处理可视化地图功能来实现前端开发,负责大数据平台相关产品的需求对接。

 2020年01月-2021年11月

• 负责海外 Apple Store 上高校系统 APP 以及全栈的设计推广落地,进行前后端开发、需求调研、竞品分析以及产品设计。

「后端开发」 华为(上海)

2018年10月-2020年01月

负责英国 4G 基站版本静态清理,通过前后端日志分析定位 MML 模块的功能,包括版本中的不继承问题等。

「前端实习」 <u>Helix House (美国)</u>

2017年08月-2018年01月

• 优化网站加载,建立测试实例,重新配置网站进行 SEO, 并启用 Hubspot / 谷歌 Analytics 进行跟踪。

2016年08月-2017年05月

● 协助 Mutsumi Nakamura 博士进行探索性和合作性学习 助教活动,定期与教授会面研讨授课内容。

「运维实习」 飞利浦(上海)

2016年05月-2016年08月

● 设计飞利浦 HSDP 战略部署、开发和支持云平台。实施压力测试来比较两个公共 laaS 提供商的虚拟机性能。

项目经历

<u>脉策数据科技</u>

万科填报后台系统

技能使用: React + Hooks + TypeScript + AntDesign + MapTalks + MobX + Datlas + Collector</u>

• 负责前端项目开发: 万科投资地图数字化平台(SaaS), 开发其填报系统 + 后台管理。

<u>脉策数据科技</u> 越秀地产城市地图 技能使用: <u>React + Hooks + TypeScript + AntDesign + MapTalks + MobX + Datlas + ECharts</u>

• 负责前端项目开发: 越秀地产客户地图与市场监测,用于甲方智能拓客以及销售检测。

脉策数据科技 花木街道物业管理 技能使用: React + Hooks + TypeScript + ArcGIS + MapTalks + MobX + Collector

• 负责前端项目开发: 花木街道数字孪生城市 - 电梯设施系统。实现跨平台开发: 电梯管理应用,加梯服务应用等。

壹龙智能科技 SeatsFinder 技能使用: <u>iOS (Swift) + ASP.NET + Web API + MVC + SQL Server (MS) + Cloud Deploy (Azure)</u>

● 跨平台校园选课、服务等多项目工具,通过抓取网站数据来进行选课: 手机端 + PC端 + 网页端 + Python端

<u>壹龙智能科技</u> StockTakes 技能使用: <u>iOS (Swift) + ASP.NET + Web API + MVC + Cloud Deploy (Azure)</u>

• 针对普华永道顾客的库存应用程序,前端于 Swift 实现部署在 iOS,使用 .NET 来完成所有后端,托管在 Azure 和 GCP 上。

自建 UI 框架 技能使用: <u>Vue 3 Composition API + Vite + TypeScript + Vue Router + SCSS</u>

• 面向开发人员、设计人员和产品经理的基于Vue 3.0的组件库。实现一个自建 UI 框架。查看更多

账记管家 技能使用: <u>Vue 2 + TypeScript + Vue Router + Vuex</u>

• 使用 Vue 完成的一个便捷记账本,能快速跟踪你的支出和收入,以及控制你的个人财务状况。 查看更多

DEE XIAO「萧笛」

+86 (186) 0164-0024 mopjtv@hotmail.com deexiao.com

PROFILE

MS graduate student from <u>Arizona State University</u> who can bring a diverse skill set and creative drive to software application development. Proficient in writing code in various languages, and feature development and implementation. Specialized in thinking outside the box to find unique solutions to difficult engineering problems.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Arizona State University - Tempe, AZ, USA GPA: 3.6 / 4.0 Aug 2012 - May 2017

Master of Science, Computer Science Arizona State University - Tempe, AZ, USA GPA: 3.4 / 4.0 Jan 2018 - Jan 2019

SKILLS

• Mobile Development (iOS & Android): Obj-C/Swift, Java/Kotlin

• BackEnd Development: C++, ASP.NET

- Web Development: React, Vue, Webpack, TS, MapTalks ...
- Version Control: Years of intensive Git & NPM experience

EXPERIENCE

FrontEnd Engineer MetroData (Shanghai)

Nov 2021 - Now

• According to the data model algorithm and geographic information, processed the visual map function to realize the front-end development, and was responsible for the demand docking of products related to the big data platform.

Full-Stack Engineer

YL Intelligent Technology (Wuxi)

Jan 2020 - Nov 2021

• Responsible for the design, promotion and implementation of university system APP. Full-Stack on overseas front-end and back-end development, demand research, competitive product analysis and design.

BackEnd Engineer

Huawei Technologies (Shanghai)

Aug 2018 - Jan 2020

- Problem Location and Optimization: Analyze and locate the functional problems of MML module.
- Code Cleanup: Responsible for the static cleaning of C++ code in the release work to ensure the code quality of the release.

FrontEnd Intern Helix House (USA)

Aug 2017 – Jan 2018

• Reconstructed Website platform to be more responsive, optimized website load, setup up testing instance, reconfigured site for SEO, and enabled Hubspot/ Google Analytics for tracking.

Teaching Assistant

Arizona State University (USA)

Aug 2016 – May 2017

Assisted Dr. Mutsumi Nakamura with exploratory and collaborative learning activities.

DevOps Intern

Philips (Shanghai) – HealthSuite Digital Platform

May 2016 – Aug 2016

- Designed Philips HSDP strategy Deploy, develop and support a cloud platform to connect health and medical devices.
- Implemented the stress testing to compare the virtual machine performance of two public laaS providers (AWS and HUAWEI Cloud).

PROJECT

Vanke Back-Stage Mgt.

MetroData (Shanghai)

React + Hooks + TypeScript + AntDesign + MapTalks + MobX + Datlas + Collector

• Vanke Investment Map digital platform (SaaS), developed its filing system and background management.

YueXiu City Map

MetroData (Shanghai)

 $\underline{\textit{React} + \textit{Hooks} + \textit{TypeScript} + \textit{AntDesign} + \textit{MapTalks} + \textit{MobX} + \textit{Datlas} + \textit{ECharts}}$

• Yuexiu Real Estate customer map and market monitoring, used for Party A's intelligent customer expansion and sales detection.

Huamu Street Mgt.

MetroData (Shanghai)

React + Hooks + TypeScript + ArcGIS + MapTalks + MobX + Collector

• Huamu Street digital Twin city-elevator facility system. Cross-platform development: elevator service management applications.

SeatsFinder

YL Intelligent Technology (Wuxi)

iOS (Swift) + ASP.NET + Web API + MVC + SQL Server (MS) + Cloud Deploy (Azure)

Cross-platform campus course selection, service and other project tools, by grasping website data to select courses.

StockTakes 5 1 1

YL Intelligent Technology (Wuxi)

iOS (Swift) + ASP.NET + Web API + MVC + Cloud Deploy (Azure)

• Inventory Counter App For PwC employers, hosted on Azure & GCP and use ASP.NET to do all back-ends

Vue 3 UI Framework

Vue 3 Composition API + Vite + TypeScript + Vue Router + SCSS

• Vue 3.0 based component library for developers, designers and product managers. (Switch, Button, Dialog, Tabs...)

Vue 2 Daybook Journal

Vue 2 + TypeScript + Vue Router + Vuex

• Application for a quick tracking of your expenses and income as well as a control over your personal financial situation.